Finding Aid for the Brainard Bartwell Cheney and Frances Neel Cheney Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Brainard Bartwell Cheney and Frances Neel Cheney Papers File Listing
  - River Rogue
    - Chapter 18 (Box 19, File 20)
    - Chapters 19-20 (Box 19, File 21)
    - Chapters 21-22 (Box 20, File 1)
    - Chapters 23-24 (Box 20, File 2)
    - Chapters 25-26 (Box 20, File 3)
    - Chapters 27-28 (Box 20, File 4)
    - Chapters 29-30 (Box 20, File 5)
    - Chapters 31-32 (Box 20, File 6)
    - Chapters 33-34 (Box 20, File 7)
    - Chapters 35-36 (Box 20, File 8)
    - Chapters 37-38 (Box 20, File 9)
    - Chapters 39-40 (Box 20, File 10)
    - Chapter 41 and Fragments (Box 20, File 11)
  - This Is Adam
    - Chapters 1-2 (Box 20, File 12)
    - Chapters 3-4 (Box 20, File 13)
    - Chapters 5-6 (Box 20, File 14)
    - Chapters 7-8 (Box 20, File 15)
    - Chapters 9-10 (Box 20, File 16)
    - Chapter 11 (Box 20, File 17)
    - Chapters 12-13 (Box 20, File 18)
    - Chapters 14-17 (Box 20, File 19)
    - Chapters 18-21 (Box 21, File 1)
    - Chapters 22-25 (Box 21, File 2)
    - Fragments (Box 21, File 3)
  - Devil’s Elbow
    - Chapter 1 (Box 21, File 4)
    - Chapter 2 (Box 21, File 5)
    - Chapters 3-4 (Box 21, File 6)
    - Chapter 5 (Box 21, File 7)
    - Chapter 6 (Box 21, File 8)
    - Chapter 7 (Box 21, File 9)
    - Chapter 8 (Box 21, File 10)
    - Chapter 9 (Box 21, File 11)
    - Chapter 10 (Box 21, File 12)
    - Chapter 11 (Box 22, File 1)
    - Chapter 12 (Box 22, File 2)
    - Chapter 13 (Box 22, File 3)
    - Chapters 14-15 (Box 22, File 4)
    - Chapter 16 (Box 22, File 5)
    - Chapters 17-18 (Box 22, File 6)
    - Chapters 19-20 (Box 22, File 7)
    - Excerpt “A River Gives Up A Murder’s Mud” (Box 22, File 8)
    - Excerpt “A River Gives Up A Murder’s Mud” Carbon Copy (Box 22, File 9)
    - Fragments, Chapters 1-3 (Box 22, File 10)
    - Fragments, Chapters 4-6 (Box 22, File 11)
    - Fragments, Chapters 7-9 (Box 22, File 12)
    - Fragments, Chapters 10-13 (Box 22, File 13)
    - Fragments, Chapters 14-16 (Box 22, File 14)
    - Fragments, Chapters 17-19 (Box 23, File 1)
    - Fragments (Box 23, File 2)
    - Fragments (Box 23, File 3)
    - Fragments (Box 23, File 4)
    - Fragments (Box 23, File 5)
    - Fragments (Box 23, File 6)
  - The Image and The Cry
    - Version A, Chapters 1-2 (Box 23, File 7)
    - Version A, Chapters 3-4 (Box 23, File 8)
    - Version A, Chapters 5-6 (Box 23, File 9)
    - Version A, Chapter 7 (Box 23, File 10)
    - Version A, Chapters 8-9 (Box 23, File 11)
    - Version A, Chapters 10-11 (Box 23, File 12)
    - Version A, Chapters 12-14 (Box 23, File 13)
    - Version A, Chapters 15-16 (Box 23, File 14)
    - Version A, Chapters 20-21 (Box 23, File 15)
    - Version A, Chapters 22-23 (Box 23, File 16)
    - Version A, Chapters 24-25 (Box 23, File 17)
    - Version A, Chapters 26-27 (Box 23, File 18)
    - Version A, Chapters 28-29 (Box 23, File 19)
    - Version A, Chapters 30-32 (Box 23, File 20)
    - Version A, Chapters 33-35, Epilogue (Box 23, File 21)
    - Version B, Chapter 1 (Box 24, File 1)
    - Version B, Chapter 2 (Box 24, File 2)
    - Version B, Chapter 3 (Box 24, File 3)
    - Version B, Chapter 4 (Box 24, File 4)
    - Version B, Chapter 5 (Box 24, File 5)
    - Version B, Chapter 6 (Box 24, File 6)
    - Version B, Chapter 7 (Box 24, File 7)
    - Version B, Chapter 8 (Box 24, File 8)
    - Version B, Chapter 9 (Box 24, File 9)
    - Version B, Chapter 10 (Box 24, File 10)
    - Version B, Chapter 11 (Box 24, File 11)
    - Version B, Chapters 12 and 14 (Box 24, File 12)
    - Version C, Prologue and Chapter 1 (Box 24, File 13)
    - Version C, Chapter 2 (Box 24, File 14)
    - Version C, Chapter 3 (Box 24, File 15)
    - Version C, Chapters 4-5 (Box 24, File 16)
    - Version C, Chapter 6 (Box 24, File 17)
    - Version C, Chapter 7 (Box 24, File 18)
    - Version C, Chapters 8-9 (Box 24, File 19)
    - Version C, Chapters 10-11 (Box 24, File 20)
    - Version C, Chapters 12-13 (Box 24, File 21)
    - Version C, Chapters 14-15 (Box 25, File 1)
    - Version C, Chapters 16-17 (Box 25, File 2)
    - Version C, Chapter 18 and Epilogue (Box 25, File 3)
    - Version D, Chapter 1 (Box 25, File 4)
    - Version D, Chapter 2 (Box 25, File 5)
    - Version D, Chapter 3 (Box 25, File 6)
    - Version D, Chapter 4 (Box 25, File 7)
    - Version D, Chapter 5 (Box 25, File 8)
    - Version E, Chapter 1 (Box 25, File 9)
    - Version E, Chapter 2 (Box 25, File 10)
    - Version E, Chapter 3 (Box 25, File 11)
    - Version E, Chapter 4 (Box 25, File 12)
    - Version E, Chapter 5 (Box 25, File 13)
    - Early Versions of the Prologue (Box 25, File 14)
    - Early Versions of Chapter 1 (Box 25, File 15)
    - Early Versions of Chapter 1 (Box 25, File 16)
    - Early Versions of Chapter 2 (Box 25, File 17)
    - Early Versions of Chapter 3 (Box 25, File 18)
    - Early Versions of Chapter 3 (Box 25, File 19)
    - Early Versions of Chapter 4 (Box 26, File 1)
    - Early Versions of Chapter 4 (Box 26, File 2)
    - Early Versions of Chapter 5 (Box 26, File 3)
    - Early Versions of Chapter 5 (Box 26, File 4)
    - Early Versions of Chapter 6 (Box 26, File 5)
    - Early Versions of Chapter 8 and 12 (Box 26, File 6)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 7)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 8)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 9)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 10)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 11)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 12)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 13)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 14)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 15)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 16)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 17)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 18)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 19)
    - Fragments (Box 26, File 20)
  - Quest For The Pelican
    - Version A, Chapters 1-3 (Box 27, File 1)
    - Version A, Chapters 4-6 (Box 27, File 2)
    - Version A, Chapters 7-9 (Box 27, File 3)
    - Version A, Chapters 10-12 (Box 27, File 4)
    - Version A, Chapters 13-15 (Box 27, File 5)
    - Version A, Chapters 16-18 (Box 27, File 6)
    - Version A, Chapters 19-20 (Box 27, File 7)
    - Version B, Chapters 3-4 (Box 27, File 8)
    - Version B, Chapters 5-6 (Box 27, File 10)
    - Version B, Chapters 7-8 (Box 27, File 11)
    - Version B, Chapters 9-10 (Box 27, File 12)
    - Version B, Chapters 11-13 (Box 27, File 13)
    - Version B, Chapters 14-15 (Box 27, File 14)
    - Version B, Chapters 16-18 (Box 27, File 15)
    - Fragments, Chapter 1 (Box 27, File 16)
    - Fragments, Chapter 2 (Box 27, File 17)
    - Fragments, Chapter 3 (Box 27, File 18)
    - Fragments, Chapters 5-6 (Box 27, File 19)
    - Fragments, Chapter 7 (Box 27, File 20)
    - Fragments, Chapter 8 (Box 28, File 1)
    - Fragments, Chapter 9 (Box 28, File 2)
    - Fragments, Chapter 9 (continued) (Box 28, File 3)
    - Fragments, Chapter 10 (Box 28, File 4)
    - Fragments, Chapter 11 (Box 28, File 5)
    - Fragments, Chapter 12 (Box 28, File 6)
    - Fragments, Chapter 13 (Box 28, File 7)
    - Fragments, Chapters 14-15 (Box 28, File 8)
    - Fragments, Chapters 16-17 (Box 28, File 9)
    - Fragments, Chapters 18-20 (Box 28, File 10)
    - Fragments, (In Search of the Pelican or The Adolescents?) (Box 28, File 11)
    - Fragments, (In Search of the Pelican or The Adolescents?) (Box 28, File 12)
    - Fragments, (In Search of the Pelican or The Adolescents?) (Box 28, File 13)
    - Fragments (Box 28, File 14)
    - Fragments (Box 28, File 15)
    - Fragments (Box 28, File 16)
    - Fragments (Box 28, File 17)
    - Fragments (Box 28, File 18)
    - Fragments (Box 28, File 19)
  - In Pursuit Of Happiness
    - Chapters 1-3 (Box 29, File 1)
    - Chapters 4-7 (Box 29, File 2)
    - Chapters 8-12 (Box 29, File 3)
    - Chapters 13-15 (Box 29, File 4)
    - Chapters 16-20 (Box 29, File 5)
    - Chapters 21-23 (Box 29, File 6)
    - Chapters 24-27 (Box 29, File 7)
    - Chapters 28-32 (Box 29, File 8)
    - “Ramp Festival” (Box 29, File 9)
    - “Political Festival” (Box 29, File 10)
    - “Political Festival” (Box 29, File 11)
    - Chapters 7-8 (Box 29, File 12)
    - Chapters 9-11 (Incomplete) (Box 29, File 13)
    - Chapters 22-24 (Box 29, File 14)
    - Chapters 25-28 (Box 29, File 15)
    - Chapters 29-31 (Box 29, File 16)
    - Chapters 32-33 (Box 29, File 17)
    - Chapters 7-10 (Box 30, File 1)
    - Chapters 17, 18, and 24 (Incomplete) (Box 30, File 2)
    - Chapters 25-29 (Box 30, File 3)
    - Chapter 30-33 (Box 30, File 4)
    - Early Version, “Ramp Festival” (Box 30, File 5)
    - Early Version, “Ramp Festival” (Box 30, File 6)
    - Fragments, 17-18 (Box 30, File 7)
    - Fragments (Box 30, File 8)
    - Fragments, Chapters 1,2,15,16, and 18 (Box 30, File 9)
    - Fragments (Box 30, File 10)
    - Fragments (Box 30, File 11)
    - Fragments (Box 30, File 12)
    - Fragments (Box 30, File 13)
    - Fragments (Box 30, File 14)
    - Fragments (Box 30, File 15)
  - The People, The People
    - Version A, Chapters 1-3 (Box 30, File 16)
    - Version A, Chapters 4-6 (Box 30, File 17)
    - Version A, Chapters 7-9 (Box 30, File 18)
    - Version A, Chapters 10-12 (Box 31, File 1)
    - Version A, Chapters 13-15 (Box 31, File 2)
    - Version A, Chapters 16-17 (Box 31, File 3)
    - Version A, Chapters 18-19 (Box 31, File 4)
    - Version B, Chapters 1-3 (Box 31, File 5)
    - Version B, Chapters 4-6 (Box 31, File 6)
    - Version B, Chapters 7-9 (Box 31, File 7)
    - Version B, Chapters 10-13 (Box 31, File 8)
    - Version B, Chapters 14-16 (Box 31, File 9)
    - Version B, Chapters 17-19 (Box 31, File 10)
    - Fragments (Box 31, File 11)
    - Fragments (Box 31, File 12)
    - Fragments (Box 31, File 13)
  - Kitty Mood’s Cup
    - Version A, Cover, Title Page, Preface, Chapters 1-2 (Box 31, File 14)
    - Version A, Chapters 3-5 (Box 31, File 15)
    - Version A, Chapters 6-8 (Box 31, File 16)
    - Version A, Chapters 9-11 (Box 31, File 17)
    - Version A, Chapters 12-14 (Box 31, File 18)
    - Version A, Chapters 15-17 (Box 31, File 19)
    - Version A, Chapters 18-20 (Box 32, File 1)
    - Version A, Chapters 21-23 (Box 32, File 2)
    - Version A, Chapters 24-26 (Box 32, File 3)
    - Version A, Chapters 27-29 (Box 32, File 4)
    - Version A, Chapters 30-31 (Box 32, File 5)
    - Version A, Chapters 32-34 (Box 32, File 6)
    - Preface, Epilogue, and Footnotes (Box 32, File 7)
    - Chapters 1-3 (Box 32, File 8)
    - Chapters 4-6 (Box 32, File 9)
    - Chapters 1-5 (Box 32, File 10)
    - Chapters 6-10 (Box 32, File 11)
    - Chapters 11-14 (Box 32, File 12)
    - Chapters 15-16 (Box 32, File 13)
    - Chapters 17-18 (Box 32, File 14)
    - Chapters 19-20 (Box 32, File 15)
    - Chapters 21-23 (Box 32, File 16)
    - Chapters 24-26 (Box 32, File 17)
    - Chapters 27-29 (Box 32, File 18)
    - Chapters 30-32 (Box 32, File 19)
    - Chapters 33-34 and Epilogue (Box 32, File 20)
    - Chapters 6-10 and undetermined Fragment (Box 32, File 21)
    - Fragments, Preface and Chapters 1-4 (Box 32, File 22)
    - Fragments, Chapters 5-7, 10 and 12 (Box 33, File 1)
    - Fragments, Chapters 14-15 (Box 33, File 2)
    - Fragments, Chapter 17 (Box 33, File 3)
    - Fragments, Chapter 18 (Box 33, File 4)
    - Fragments, Chapter 21 (Box 33, File 5)
    - Fragments, Chapters 22-23 (Box 33, File 6)
    - Fragments, Chapter 24 (Box 33, File 7)
    - Fragments, Chapter 25 (Box 33, File 8)
    - Fragments, Chapters 26-27 (Box 33, File 9)
    - Fragments, Chapters 28-29 (Box 33, File 10)
    - Fragments, Chapters 30-31 (Box 33, File 11)
    - Fragments, Chapters 32-34 and Epilogue (Box 33, File 12)
    - Fragments (Box 33, File 13)
    - Fragments (Box 33, File 14)
    - Fragments (Box 33, File 15)
    - Fragments (Box 33, File 16)
    - Fragments (Box 33, File 17)
    - Fragments (Box 33, File 18)
    - Fragments (Box 33, File 19)
    - Fragments (Box 33, File 20)
    - Fragments (Box 33, File 21)
    - Fragments (Box 33, File 22)
    - Fragments (Box 33, File 23)
  - A Time To Come To
    - Prologue, Chapters 1-3 (Box 34, File 1)
    - Chapters 4-6 (Box 34, File 2)
    - Chapters 7-9 (Box 34, File 3)
    - Chapters 10-12 (Box 34, File 4)
    - Chapters 13-15 (Box 34, File 5)
    - Chapters 16-17 (Box 34, File 6)
    - Chapter 18 and Epilogue (Box 34, File 7)
    - Fragments (Box 34, File 8)
    - Fragments (Box 34, File 9)
    - Fragments, Epilogue (Box 34, File 10)
  - Writings, Plays
  - Strangers in This World
    - Act I, Scenes I, II, and III (Box 34, File 11)
    - Act II, Scenes I, II, and two different Scene III (Box 34, File 12)
    - Act III, Scenes I, II, and III (Box 34, File 13)
    - Act III, Scenes I, II, and IV (Box 34, File 14)
    - Fragments, Title Page, List of Characters, List of Scenes, Epilogue (Box 34, File 15)
    - Fragments, Act III (Box 34, File 16)
    - Fragments, Act III (Box 34, File 17)
    - Fragments (Box 34, File 18)
    - Fragments (Box 34, File 19)
    - Fragments (Box 34, File 20)
    - Fragments (Box 34, File 21)
    - Photocopies of Several Fragments (Box 34, File 22)
    - Photocopy in Entirety (Box 34, File 23)
  - I Choose To Die
    - Version A, Prologue, Act I, Scenes I, II, and III, Entr’acte (Box 35, File 1)
    - Version A, Act II, Scenes I, II, and III, Entr’acte (Box 35, File 2)
    - Version A, Act III, Scenes I, II, III, and IV and Epilogue (Box 35, File 3)
    - Version A, Prologue, Act I, Scenes I, II, and III, Entr’acte (Box 35, File 4)
    - Version A, Act II, Scenes I, II, and III, Entr’acte (Box 35, File 5)
    - Version A, Act III, Scenes I, II, III and IV, and Epilogue (Box 35, File 6)
    - Version B, Prologue, Act I, Scenes I, II, and III, Entr’acte (Box 35, File 7)
    - Version B, Act II, Scenes I, II, III, and IV, Entr’acte (Box 35, File 8)
    - Version B, Act III, Scenes I, II, III, and IV, and Epilogue (Box 35, File 9)
    - Version C, Prologue, Act I, Scenes I, II, and III, Entr’acte (Box 35, File 10)
    - Version C, Act II, Scenes I, II, III and IV, Entr’acte (Box 35, File 11)
    - Version C, Act III, Scenes I, II, III, and IV and Epilogue (Box 35, File 12)
    - Early Versions, Overture and Act I, Scene I (Box 35, File 13)
    - Early Versions, Act I, Scenes II and III and Entr’acte (Box 35, File 14)
    - Early Versions, Act II, Scenes I and II (Box 35, File 15)
    - Early Versions, Act II, Scenes III and IV and Entr’acte (Box 35, File 16)
    - Early Versions, Act III, Scenes I and II (Box 35, File 17)
    - Early Versions, Act III, Scenes III and IV and Epilogue (Box 35, File 18)
    - Bound Copy (Box 35, File 19)
    - Alumnus Magazine Galley Proof, Act I, Scene I and Act III, Scene IV (Box 35, File 20)
  - Writings, Stories
    - A Page Out Of The Diary Of A Southern Liberal’s Past (Box 36, File 1)
    - Catfish Escape (Box 36, File 2)
    - Get On Board Little Children (Box 36, File 3)
    - The Invisible Chains (Box 36, File 4)
    - Keep A Wet Finger To The Wind (Box 36, File 5)
    - Life Sentence (Box 36, File 6)
    - Lightning (Box 36, File 7)
    - Occupied Country * A Backward Glance (Box 36, File 8)
    - The Plaything, Version A (Box 36, File 9)
    - The Plaything, Version B (Box 36, File 10)
    - The Plaything, Chapters 1-3 (Box 36, File 11)
    - The Plaything, Chapters 1-3 (Box 36, File 12)
    - The Plaything, Fragments (Box 36, File 13)
    - The Plaything, Fragments (Box 36, File 14)
    - The Plaything, Fragments (Box 36, File 15)
    - The Plaything, Fragments (Box 36, File 16)
    - The Plaything, Fragments (Box 36, File 17)
    - The Plaything, Fragments (Box 36, File 18)
    - The Spirit Of The Bayonet (Box 36, File 19)
    - Uncle John’s Reward (Box 36, File 20)
    - World Beyond Words (Box 36, File 20a)
    - The Yellow Dress (Box 36, File 21)
    - Untitled (Box 36, File 22)
    - Untitled (Box 36, File 23)
    - Untitled (Box 36, File 24)
    - Untitled (Box 36, File 25)
    - Untitled (Box 36, File 26)
    - Untitled (Box 36, File 27)
    - Untitled (Box 36, File 28)
    - Untitled (Box 36, File 29)
    - Untitled (Box 36, File 30)
    - Untitled (Box 36, File 31)
    - Untitled (Box 36, File 32)
    - Untitled, Fragments (Box 36, File 33)
    - Untitled, Fragments (Box 36, File 34)
  - Writings, Reviews
    - Anderson, William- The Wild Man From Sugar Creek: The Political Career of Eugene Talmadge (Box 37, File 1)
    - Buckley, William F.- Up From Liberalism (Box 37, File 2)
    - Davidson, Donald- Still Rebels, Still Yankees (Box 37, File 3)
    - Esfandiary, Fereidoun- The Day Of Sacrifice (Box 37, File 4)
    - Geiger, Maynard J.- The Life And Times Of Fray Junipero Serra (Box 37, File 5)
    - Gordon, Caroline- The Malefactors (Box 37, File 6)
    - Green, Ely- Ely (Box 37, File 7)
    - Hartley, Lodwick and George Core, eds.- Katherine Anne Porter: A Critical Symposium (Box 37, File 8)
    - Key, V.O.- Southern Politics (Box 37, File 9)
    - Kirk, Russell- Enemies Of The Permanent Things (Box 37, File 10)
    - Koch, Vivian- Change Of Love (Box 37, File 11)
    - Lukacs, John- The Passing Of The Modern Age (Box 37, File 12)
    - Lytle, Andrew- The Velvet Horn (Box 37, File 13)
    - O’Connor, Flannery- Wise Blood (Box 37, File 14)
    - O’Connor, Flannery- The Violent Bear It Away (Box 37, File 14)
    - Opotowsky, Stan- The Longs Of Louisiana (Box 37, File 15)
    - Percy, Walker- The Last Gentleman (Box 37, File 16)
    - Peterkin, Julia- The Collected Short Stories Of Julia Peterkin, ed. Frank Grisham (Box 37, File 17)
    - Rubin, Louis D.- The Lasting South (Box 37, File 18)
    - Sullivan, Walter- The Long, Long, Love (Box 37, File 19)
    - Truman, Harry S.- Mr. Citizen (Box 37, File 20)
    - Warren, Robert Penn- (Four separate reviews) (Box 37, File 21)
    - Watkins, Floyd C. - Then and Now: The Personal Past in the Poetry of Robert Penn Warren (Box 37, File 22)
  - Writings, Articles and Essays
    - Adventure II Series, for Nashville Banner, April 3, 1939-April 24, 1939- Complete Clippings (Box 37, File 23)
    - Adventure II Series, for Nashville Banner, April 3, 1939-April 24, 1939- Incomplete Clippings (Box 37, File 24)
    - Adventure II Series, for the Nashville Banner, April 3, 1939-April 15, 1939- Typed copy (Box 37, File 25)
    - Adventure II Series, for the Nashville Banner, April 16, 1939-April 24, 1939- Typed copy (Box 37, File 26)
    - Adventure II Series, for the Nashville Banner, Personal Journal (Box 37, File 27)
    - Adventure II Series, for the Nashville Banner, April 2-April 6, 1939, Clippings (Box 37, File 28)
    - Adventure II Series, for the Nashville Banner, April 7-Undated, Clippings (Box 37, File 29)
    - Can The Common Man Convert To Color? (Box 37, File 30)
    - Can The Common Man Convert To Color? (Box 37, File 31)
    - Caroline Gordon’s Ontological Quest (Box 37, File 32)
    - Clement Machine (Box 37, File 33)
    - The Crocodile Or The Crucifix: The Politics Of Syncretism, Toynbee-ism, And Revelation (Box 37, File 34)
    - The Crocodile Or The Crucifix (Box 37, File 35)
    - The Dixiecrat’s Dilemma (Box 37, File 36)
    - Has Teilhard de Chardin Really Joined The Within And Without Of Things? (Box 37, File 37)
    - The History Of My Arthritis (Box 37, File 38)
    - Howard Johnson’s Meals For Millions (Box 38, File 1)
    - Jesus’ Trial Of Will (Box 38, File 2)
    - Jesus’ Trial Of Will (Box 38, File 3)
    - The Leader Follows-Where? (Box 38, File 4)
    - Letters to the Editor (Box 38, File 5)
    - Light Of Communication Theory On The Biologic System (Box 38, File 6)
    - Light Of Communication Theory On The Biologic System, Early Versions (Box 38, File 7)
    - Light Of Communication Theory On The Biologic System, Fragments (Box 38, File 8)
    - Lightwood- for The Constitution; Atlanta, Georgia; Sunday, November 26, 1939 (Box 38, File 9)
    - Travel DeLuxe: The Lumber Way- Rich’s Book Album, Sunday, December 1, 1940 (Box 38, File 10)
    - “Look-a, Look-a Yonder- I See Sunday, I See Sunday!” Or, A Deliverer, Delivered (Box 38, File 11)
    - Miss O’Connor’s Humor Is Funnier Than Mr. Hawkes’ Joke, And, Better Grounded (Box 38, File 12)
    - The Myth Of Modern Science (Box 38, File 13)
    - A New Crown Of Thorns For The Democratic Party (Box 38, File 14)
    - Peter Taylor’s Plays (Box 38, File 15)
    - Response To Protestant Attacks On The Catholic Church (Box 38, File 16)
    - To Restore A Fragmented Image (Box 38, File 17)
    - Source Of Meaning (Box 38, File 18)
    - Teilhard de Chardin As A Philosopher Of Science (Box 38, File 19)
    - Teilhard de Chardin’s Call To Coherence (Box 38, File 20)
    - Teilhard de Chardin’s Call To Coherence (Box 38, File 21)
    - True Time and Motivation (Box 38, File 22)
    - Uncertainty of Survival: Cradle of Consciousness?, Co-written with Antonio Gotto (Box 39, File 1)
    - Uncertainty of Survival: Cradle of Consciousness?, Co-written with Antonio Gotto (Box 39, File 2)
    - Uncertainty of Survival: Cradle of Consciousness?, Fragments (Box 39, File 3)
    - What The Genetic Theory Of Consciousness Signifies For Evolution, History, Religion Co-written with Antonio Gotto (Box 39, File 4)
    - Teilhard de Chardin Fragments (Box 39, File 5)
    - Teilhard de Chardin Fragments (Box 39, File 6)
    - Teilhard de Chardin Fragments (Box 39, File 7)
  - Writings, Memoirs
    - Chapter 2 (Box 39, File 8)
    - Chapter 13 and 14 and Fragment (Box 39, File 9)
  - Writings, Eulogies
    - Bess, Robin- “Of The Old South, A Catharsis-A Personal Testimony” (Box 39, File 10)
    - Davidson, Donald (Box 39, File 11)
    - Gordon, Caroline (Box 39, File 12)
    - McGill, Ralph (Box 39, File 13)
    - Moss, Charles (Box 39, File 14)
    - Smith, Hoke (Box 39, File 15)
    - Willcox, Reid (Box 39, File 16)
  - Writings, Speeches
    - Address By Governor Frank Clement, Given to the International Council for Christian Leadership, February 3, 1955, Ghost Written by Brainard Cheney (Box 39, File 17)
    - An Exile’s Return to the Altamaha by Brainard Cheney (Box 39, File 17a)
    - Flannery O’Connor, Given at Peabody, no date (Box 39, File 18)
    - The Novelist As Myth-Maker, Given to Nashville Public School Teachers of English, October 20, 1960 (Box 39, File 19)
    - Remarks before The Serra Club, 1957?, (topic-Conversion to Catholicism) (Box 39, File 20)
    - Remarks on Small Business Situation, Given by Senator Tom Stewart, February 22, 1943, Ghost Written by Brainard Cheney (Box 39, File 21)
    - River Trip, by Brainard Cheney (Box 39, File 21a)
    - The South And Its Future, Given by Governor Frank Clement to the Atlanta Chamber of Commerce, April 15, 1953, Ghost Written by Brainard Cheney (Box 39, File 22)
    - Teilhard de Chardin, on the fourteen anniversary of his death (Box 39, File 23)
  - Writings, Movie Script
    - Not Enough To Go Around (Box 39, File 24)
  - Writings, Academic Work
    - School Essay Exams, Four English and One Sociology (Box 39, File 25)
  - Writings, Verse
    - 10 items of Verse (Box 39, File 26)
  - Writings, Reviews
    - Bell, Madison Smart- The Washington Square Ensemble (Box 39, File 27)
    - Bowen, John- The Center Of The Green (Box 39, File 28)
    - Givner, Joan- Katherine Anne Porter: A Life (Box 39, File 29)
  - Writings, Articles and Essays
    - Reference Books, An Ever Present Help In Trouble- Reference Services Review, Summer 1983 (Box 39, File 30)
    - Books and Reading In The Modern World- in Great Human Issues Of Our Times (Box 39, File 31)
  - Writings, Speeches
    - Fugitives, Given to Volunteer State Community College, Nashville History Extension Course, November 1, 1979 (Box 39, File 32)
    - Katherine Anne Porter and Her Biographer, Woman’s Club, March 5, 1984 (Box 39, File 33)
  - Publication Materials
  - Lightwood
    - Research (Box 40, File 1)
    - Research (Box 40, File 2)
    - Research, Clippings (Box 40, File 3)
    - Research (Box 40, File 4)
    - Outline/Summary (Box 40, File 5)
    - Character Sketches (Box 40, File 6)
    - Chapter Outlines (Box 40, File 7)